### **Blaise Irakoze**

Kigali, Rwanda +25078821179

blaiseirakoze50@gmail.com

https://github.com/blaiseirakoze

https://www.linkedin.com/in/blaise-irakoze-2124a812b

## **Summary**

I am a software engineer with 3 years of professional experience. I build products ranging from web applications, mobile applications and backend Apis. I am efficient in different technologies including Java, JavaScript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS, SpringBoot and others.

# **Experience**

AUGUST 2021 - PRESENT

Qtsoftwareltd(<u>https://qtglobal.rw/</u>), Kigali - Software engineer

- System analysis.
- Full Stack web development.

JULY 2020 - AUGUST 2021

Guaranty Trust Bank(Rwanda) Plc(<a href="https://www.gtbank.co.rw/">https://www.gtbank.co.rw/</a>), Kigali - Software engineer

- Inhouse solutions development.
- Monitor, analyze and report performance statistics for internal systems.
- Developing new internal and external entities.

MAY 2019 - AUGUST 2019

#### MINECOFIN(IFMIS)(<a href="https://www.minecofin.gov.rw/">https://www.minecofin.gov.rw/</a>), Kigali - Intern

- Learn technologies such as spring framework, hibernate, ZK, maven, SVN, web services, unit and integration test, messaging brokers like kafka, .....
- Join a software analysis team for a new application analysis.
- Workshop.

#### Education

SEPTEMBER 2015 - NOVEMBER 2020

Adventist University Of Central Africa, Kigali - Ao

I hold a bachelor degree of information technology focused in software engineering.

#### Skills



# **Recent projects**

OCTOBER 2021

#### **E-correspondence - QTsoftwareltd**

This is a portal where banks, insurances and others access BNR services.

FEBRUARY 2022 - APRIL 2022

#### OCF App(Online Collect Funds) - Groupeya ltd

This is a mobile application used to send funds to someone in need. It's integrated with MTN so that the funds go directly to MOMO(MTN Mobile Money) of the fund.

MARCH 2021

#### GT Mobile - Guaranty Trust Bank(Rwanda) Plc

This is a GTBank ussd application runs on \*600#. It contains different services such as sending money, paying utilities(electricity, water, ...), bank services and you can check your accounts status and statements.

DECEMBER 2020 - MAY 2022

#### **Quikss - Personal project**

This is a mobile application that helps people to access hotels and restaurants' menus and be able press and track their order. It also has a web application for hotel/restaurant internal management. http://quickss-web.herokuapp.com

DECEMBER 2020 - APRIL 2021

#### Digital archive - Guaranty Trust Bank(Rwanda) Plc

This is a GTBank inhouse portal used to manage and store clients account files and all other related files.

JULY 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2020

#### MTN Real time liquidation - Guaranty Trust Bank(Rwanda) Plc

This is a GTBank integration with a tele-communication organization (MTN) used by their vendors who use GTBank accounts to initiate and receive their payments in real time.

JUNE 2019 - MAY 2020

#### ECMS(Electronic claim management system) - E-baza

This is a system that is involved in car maintenance and brought the gap to the study on how to recover losses in companies and break the corruption system in vehicle maintenance. https://umuhuza.rw/

#### **IT Certificates**

#### **Employment certificate from Guaranty Trust Bank(Rwanda) Plc**

- This is a certificate given by GTBank to the employee
- Dates: From 3 rd July, 2020 to 13 th August, 2021
- Skills: Banking system and software development

#### **React frontend to back from udemy**

- This a certificate given to people who successfully attended the bootcamp
- Dated: from 20th may 2019
- Skills: Reactjs, React router, Axios, Redux

#### Honors

The first marks of a good final project in IT faculty at AUCA(Adventist University of Central Africa) – 2019.

# Languages

English - Fluent

Kinyarwanda – *Native* 

French - Basic

#### **Interests**

